Let's take a quick look at some of the key things that Flexbox can do.
لنلق نظرة سريعة على بعض الأمور الأساسية التي يمكن لـ «فليكس بوكس» القيام بها.
I'm going to do that without giving too much explanation,
سأفعل ذلك دون الخوض بالتفاصيل
just because I want to give you an idea of what Flexbox is.
لأعطيكم فكرة عن «فليكس بوكس».
Then step-by-step, we'll go through and teach how to do each of them.
بعد ذلك سنتعلم بالتفصيل وخطوة خطوة كيفية استخدامه
Here, you can see that I have set up.
كما ترون قمت بضبط الإعداد هنا.
Let's take a look at the HTML first,
لنلق نظرة على HTML أولًا،
a div with a class container,
لدينا قسم (div) من فئة (class) حاوية
and then inside of that,
وبداخله،
I have three divs with the class box,
ثلاثة أقسام من فئة مربع (box)
and each of them has a different ID,
ولكل منها معرّف مختلف،
one, two, and three.
واحد، اثنان، وثلاثة.
So one thing I could do is simply change my flex direction from column to row,
يمكن مثلًا تغيير الاتجاه المرن من عمود إلى صف،
and you see that it has changed the alignment of the boxes inside.
وعندئذ تتغير محاذاة المربعات بالداخل.
So now if you look,
فإذا نظرنا،
you can see that my three boxes are in a row.
سنجد أن المربعات الثلاثة موجودة في صف واحد.
But again, column and they are in a column.
وعند اختيار عمود ثانية، تصطف في عمود.
What about column reverse?
ماذا عن خاصية عكس العمود (column reverse)؟
So here it's box one,
كما نرى، هذا المربع الأول،
box two, box three.
المربع الثاني، المربع الثالث.
Now, that we refreshed it's box three,
لكن بعد التحديث، يتغير الترتيب فهذا المربع الثالث،
box two, box one.
ثم المربع الثاني ثم المربع الأول.
Let's go back to a row for a second.
لنعد للترتيب الأفقي في صف من جديد.
Let's try changing how we justify our content.
ونجرب تغيير كيفية ضبط المحتوى.
You can see that each of the three boxes
يمكننا أن نلاحظ أن كلًا من المربعات الثلاثة
also have some of their own individual CSS properties.
لديه خصائص CSS الخاصة به.
The one that I want us to look at right this second is just called order.
والخاصية التي نريد التحدث عنها الآن هي الرتبة (order)
Right now they all have an order of one.
جميع المربعات لها رتبة تساوي واحد.
So there are ordered one, two, three.
وتظهر مرتبة واحد، اثنان، ثلاثة.
But watch what happens when I drop the order of one and
راقبوا ماذا يحصل عندما أحول الرتبة للمربع واحد
two to three and leave the order property of div three at one.
واثنان إلى ثلاثة، وأترك خاصية الرتبة للقسم (div) ثلاثة بالقيمة واحد.
You see that box three is now first because it comes in
نلاحظ أن المربع ثلاثة أصبح في أول الصف حسب
the order or of columns like this.
الرتبة، وإذا كان في عمود يبدو بهذا الشكل.
If we don't want to align in the item center,
إذا لم نرد محاذاة العنصر في الوسط،
we move them over there.
ننقله بهذا الشكل إلى هناك.
There's all stuff that you can do once you start to take control with Flexbox.
هناك الكثير من الأمور التي يمكنك أن تقوم بها بعد أن تتقن استخدام «فليكس بوكس»
Let's dive deeper so that you can learn the real skills underlying
سننتقل إلى الحديث عنه بالتفصيل لتتعلم المهارات التي
the movements we're making and set up your pixel perfect website.
تمكنك ضبط الأمور وإنشاء موقع إلكتروني بدقة متناهية